University Of Connecticut 1990.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Affirmative Action Office Records
1971-1993.
1990.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
18.0 Linear feet
The collection contains materials pertaining to the development and publication of the University's Affirmative Action policy. The name of the office was changed in the 1990s to the Office of Diversity and Equity.
Office for Affirmative Action.
History
The Office of Diversity and Equity (ODE) (formerly Office for Affirmative Action) supports the University's commitment to diversity, multiculturalism, social equity, and affirmative action by providing advice and services. ODE advises the President, executive and senior administration on institutional civil rights and social equity policies, issues and problems. Individually and in collaboration with other divisions and units, the office develops and implements programs and activities to promote a positive campus environment. ODE manages special projects for the retention of minorities and women and diversity training programs that require central oversight. The office monitors the University's compliance with and develops activities to support the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). ODE investigates complaints of discrimination and discriminatory harassment, and manages all pre-litigation civil rights cases filed against the University with state and federal enforcement agencies. The office prepares the University's Affirmative Action Plan for Employment (state and federal versions); monitors employment systems, including search policies and procedures; and assists the University administration on matters relating to institutional compliance. ODE engages in outreach activities to campus units and external groups in the state, region, and nation.
Scope and Content
The collection contains materials pertaining to the development and publication of the University's Affirmative Action policy.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Affirmative Action Plan (recent issues) Dodd Periodicals
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were transferred from the Office of Affirmative Action. Copies of the University's Plan are forwarded from the Reserve Desk at Homer Babbidge Library as they are superceded.
University of Connecticut--Officals and employees--Recruiting.; University of Connecticut. Office for Affirmative Action Programs.; University of Connecticut. Office of Diversity and Equity.; Affiramtive action programs in education--United States.; Affirmative action programs--Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Publications.; Reports.; Universities and colleges--Administration.; Universities.
- Series I: Records, 1971-1993
  - Final Draft, Uconn's Equal Employment (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Opportunity Program for Construction, 1971
  - AAP Plan, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Departmental plans, 1971-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - AAP plan, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 4-6)
  - AAP plan program development, 1972-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Departmental plans, 1971-1973 (Box 1:, Folder 8-10)
  - Departmental plans, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 11-14)
  - AAP reporting forms, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - Response to HEW Report of Findings, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - UConn Affirmative Action plan, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 17-19)
  - Affirmative Action Plans
    - Schools and Colleges (Box 3:, Folder 20-28)
    - Schools and Colleges (Box 4:, Folder 29-37)
    - Centers and Institutes (Box 5:, Folder 38)
    - Staff Services (Box 5:, Folder 39)
    - Departmental plans (Box 5:, Folder 40-42)
    - Departmental plans (Box 6-7:, Folder 43-52)
    - Departmental plans (Box 8:, Folder 53-54)
    - Program development, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 55)
    - Historical data, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 56-57)
    - Program development, 1974-1975 (Box 8:, Folder 58-60)
    - Affirmative Action Plan Committee, 1974 (Box 8:, Folder 61-62)
  - AAP Plans, 1976-1977 (Box 9:, Folder 63-64)
  - President's Statement of Policy on Equal, 1977 (Box 9:, Folder 65)
  - Employment Opportunity, 1977
  - AAP Plans, 1977 (Box 9:, Folder 66-69)
  - AAP Plans, 1977 (Box 10:, Folder 70-73)
  - Equal Opportunity Office, 1977 (Box 10:, Folder 74-77)
  - Equal Opportunity Office, 1977 (Box 11:, Folder 78-81)
  - AAP Plans, 1978 (Box 11:, Folder 82-84)
  - AAP Plans, 1978 (Box 12:, Folder 85-90)
  - AAP Plans, 1978 (Box 13:, Folder 91-93)
  - Analysis of Promotions among non-classified job categories, 1978 (Box 13:, Folder 94-97)
  - Analysis of Promotions among non-classified job categories, 1978 (Box 14:, Folder 98-99)
  - AAP Plans, 1979 (Box 14:, Folder 100-104)
  - AAP Plans, 1979 (Box 15:, Folder 105-111)
  - AAP Plans (Box 16)
    - Abridged, 1979 (Box 16:, Folder 112)
    - Health Center, 1979 (Box 16:, Folder 113-117)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Office policy statements, 1975-1979 (Box 16:, Folder 118)
  - AAP Plans, 1980 (Box 16:, Folder 119)
  - AAP Plans, 1980-1981 (Box 17:, Folder 120-126)
  - Affirmative Action Program office memoranda, 1981 (Box 17:, Folder 127)
  - Professional Search Administration handbook, 1981 (Box 17:, Folder 128)
  - AAP Plans, 1983-1985 (Box 17:, Folder 129-136)
  - Affirmative Action: President's statement, 1984 (Box 17:, Folder 137)
  - Revision and clarification of existing search procedures, 1984 (Box 17:, Folder 138)
  - AAP Plans, 1984-1985 (Box 17:, Folder 139-140)
  - AAP Plans, 1984-1986 (Box 20:, Folder 141-147)
  - AAP Plans, 1986-1987 (Box 21:, Folder 148-152)
  - AAP Plans, 1987 (Box 22:, Folder 153-156)
  - AAP Plans, 1987 (Box 23:, Folder 157-163)
  - AAP Plans, 1987-1988 (Box 24:, Folder 164-172)
  - AAP Plans, 1988 (Box 25:, Folder 173-178)
  - AAP Plans, 1989 (Box 26:, Folder 179-184)
  - AAP Plans, 1989 (Box 27:, Folder 185-187)
  - Affirmative Action Plan for Employment, 1990 (Box 27:, Folder 188)
  - AAP Plans, 1990 (Box 28:, Folder 189-192)
  - AAP Plans, 1990 (Box 29:, Folder 193-196)
    - Abridged, 1992 (Box 29:, Folder 197)
  - AAP Plans, 1991 (Box 30:, Folder 198-199)
  - AAP Plans, 1992 (Box 31:, Folder 200-201)
  - AAP Plans, 1993 (Box 32:, Folder 202-203)
  - AAP Plans, 1994-1995 (Box 33:, Folder 204-206)
  - AAP Plans, 1996-1997 (Box 33:, Folder 207)
  - AAP Plans, 1996-1997 (Box 34:, Folder 208-214)